<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <!--
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_0_paragraph_0"></string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_0_texto_buscado_0"></string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_0_title_0"></string>
    -->

    <!--PANTALLA 1-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_0_paragraph_0">The first stages in human history are named after the materials that have driven major transformations: Stone, Copper, Bronze and Iron. To these materials are added others such as glass, ceramics and polymers, which played a key role in the Modern and Contemporary Ages.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_0_texto_buscado_0">Stone, Copper, Bronze and Iron</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_0_paragraph_1">In 2020, a study estimated that the weight of all human-made artificial materials was already equal to that of the entire biomass (living matter) of the planet. In developed countries, it\'s estimated that between 80% and 95% of what\'s around us are artificial compounds.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_0_texto_buscado_1">was already equal</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_0_paragraph_2">The paper, one of the most important material inventions, facilitated the transmission of knowledge much more accessible than its predecessors such as papyrus or parchment. Its use in printing has multiplied literary production by 3000%.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_0_texto_buscado_2"> the transmission of knowledge</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 2-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_1_paragraph_0">Other material advances have had more contradictory impacts. Gunpowder transformed the war, making it more cruel, but it was also instrumental in the development of mining and public works. Penicillin, discovered centuries later, saved millions of lives. </string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_1_texto_buscado_0">transformed the war</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_1_paragraph_1">The contrast is also evident in everyday objects: the environmental impact of a ceramic container is incomparable with that of a plastic one, and the emissions of a gasoline car far exceed those of a renewable energy driven ones.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_1_texto_buscado_1">and the emissions of a gasoline car</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 3-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_2_paragraph_0">New materials research has been a driving force for progress in areas as diverse as medicine, industry, transportation and art. It has enabled us to respond to the challenges of each epoch and is seen as one of the most important tools for building a more sustainable future.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_2_texto_buscado_0">medicine, industry, transportation and art</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_2_paragraph_1">With this aim iMATUS was born, as one of the ten research institutes of the University of Santiago de Compostela. Its mission is to offer solutions to current and future challenges from a transdisciplinary perspective focused on the study of materials.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_2_texto_buscado_1" translatable="false">iMATUS</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 4-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_3_paragraph_0">The Materials Institute, iMATUS, is a research centre of excellence created in December 2020 with the aim of developing new materials and improving existing ones, with applications in fields as diverse as nanotechnology, biomedicine, renewable energies, electronics or communications.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_3_texto_buscado_0">created in December 2020</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_3_paragraph_1">Located on the Campus Vida of the University of Santiago de Compostela, iMATUS has modern facilities and laboratories equipped to conduct cutting-edge research. Its team consists of more than 110 people, including researchers and technical staff, with 42% of women. Its areas of work cover disciplines such as pharmacy, food science, chemistry, physics or optics.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_3_texto_buscado_1" translatable="false">Campus Vida</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_3_texto_buscado_2">more than 110 people</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_3_paragraph_2">iMATUS maintains collaborations with universities, research centres, and companies, both nationally and internationally. One of its main commitments is the transfer of knowledge, bringing laboratory advances into the real world through solutions that address the major social, economic, and environmental challenges of today and tomorrow.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_3_texto_buscado_3">universities, research centres, and companies, both nationally and internationally</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 5-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_4_paragraph_0">Research at iMATUS is organized into three major areas:</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_4_texto_buscado_0">three major areas</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_4_paragraph_1">Materials for health</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_4_paragraph_2">Materials for industry and emerging technologies</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_4_paragraph_3">Materials for energy and the environment</string>
    <!--PANTALLA 6-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_5_title_0">MATERIALS FOR HEALTH</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_5_paragraph_0">The rise in diseases associated with changes in the lifestyle of modern society has highlighted the need to develop new tools for detection and treatment. Among the main challenges are early diagnosis in asymptomatic phases and personalization of treatments, with the aim of minimizing unwanted side effects in patients. To address these challenges, it is key to promote technologies that allow early diagnosis and better treatment. Some of the progress made is as follows.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_5_texto_buscado_0">the need to develop new tools for detection and treatment</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_5_title_1">Adapted medicines development:</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_5_texto_buscado_1">Adapted medicines development: </string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_5_paragraph_1">Development of specialized treatments for diseases that do not have a commercial medicine available, and that adapt to the specific needs of each patient. A prominent example is personalized medicines for children with rare diseases, which ensure the effectiveness and safety of their treatments.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_5_texto_buscado_2">personalized medicines for children with rare diseases</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_5_title_2">Regenerative medicine:</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_5_texto_buscado_3">Regenerative medicine:</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_5_paragraph_2">Through the creation of structures known as scaffolds, inspired by organic or biological forms, it is possible to stimulate regeneration of damaged tissues. These scaffolds are made from biocompatible materials, which avoid rejection by the organism, while stimulating tissue repair.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_5_texto_buscado_4">avoid rejection by the organism</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_5_title_3">Alternative methods of animal research:</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_5_texto_buscado_5">Alternative methods of animal research:</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_5_paragraph_3">Develop artificial organs and disease models to improve the validity of preclinical trial results, while avoiding the technical and ethical challenges associated with research on living beings.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_5_texto_buscado_6">avoiding the technical and ethical</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 7-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_6_title_0">MATERIALS FOR INDUSTRY AND EMERGING TECHNOLOGIES</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_6_paragraph_0">The development of new materials that promote technological advances is essential to ensure the sustainability and viability of these innovations. Some of these materials are based on emerging technologies, such as photonics or quantum physics, and promise to play a key role in supercomputing and transmitting information at high speeds. Among the projects associated with this branch of research are:</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_6_texto_buscado_0">sustainability and viability</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_6_title_1">Photonic materials and quantum computation:</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_6_texto_buscado_1">Photonic materials and quantum computation:</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_6_paragraph_1">Encryption capacity and speed in communications, especially when it comes to sensitive information, are essential to preserve their safety. This is why studies are carried out in photonic materials, which allow faster and more accurate information transmissions, and in quantum computing, which enables much safer data encryption systems.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_6_texto_buscado_2">to preserve their safety</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_6_title_2">Advanced heterogeneous catalysts:</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_6_texto_buscado_3">Advanced heterogeneous catalysts:</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_6_paragraph_2">In order to improve chemical processes, iMATUS develops materials that act as catalysts capable of activating chemical reactions without wearing out. These reusable catalysts allow for more accurate and efficient reactions, which contributes to reducing the energy consumption and environmental impact of numerous synthesis processes.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_6_texto_buscado_4">catalysts capable of activating chemical reactions</string>


    <!--PANTALLA 8-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_7_title_0">MATERIALS FOR ENERGY AND ENVIRONMENT</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_7_paragraph_0">It is essential to find more sustainable solutions that reduce the environmental impact of human activities without compromising quality of life. This involves research focused both on energy efficiency and on the reduction of environmental pollution. Below are some of the research projects that the Institute develops within this line.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_7_texto_buscado_0">the environmental impact</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_7_title_1">Clean energy with better performance:</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_7_texto_buscado_1">Clean energy with better performance:</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_7_paragraph_1">The development of nanolubricants for wind mills (wind turbines) allows optimization of energy production by reducing friction between its components. In addition, iMATUS investigates the design of advanced devices for energy storage and new methods of hydrogen production as a clean source.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_7_texto_buscado_2">optimization of energy production</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_7_title_2">Detection of microplastics:</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_7_texto_buscado_3">Detection of microplastics:</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_7_paragraph_2">The increase in pollutants that are difficult to eliminate, such as microplastics and various chemical agents, requires the development of effective systems for the detection and elimination of the environment. iMATUS develops intensive research in the development of trap systems.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_7_texto_buscado_4">pollutants that are difficult to eliminate</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 9-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_8_paragraph_0">The research carried out on iMATUS has a strong local impact, thanks to collaborations that connect science with tradition, industry and citizenship. The iMATUS transfer strategy is based on a permanent dialogue with all social sectors, from mining and raw materials industries to technology-based companies and the clinical field, in order to respond to the real demands of society.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_8_texto_buscado_0">permanent dialogue with all social sectors</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 10-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_9_paragraph_0">A prominent example is the cooperation with the artisanal trade of Black Amber and silver of Santiago to guarantee the authenticity of the Black Amber used in the elaboration of the pieces of jewellery from Santiago de Compostela, or the collaboration in industrial tests with the ceramic factory of Sargadelos. The institute is also committed to the reuse and optimization of materials derived from industrial by-products and the agro-forestry sector, to promote the circular economy and sustainability.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_9_texto_buscado_0">collaboration in industrial tests with the ceramic factory of Sargadelos</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_9_paragraph_1">In addition to its social commitment, iMATUS carries out important scientific dissemination efforts through its own training activities, as well as in collaboration with the University of Santiago de Compostela (USC) and other institutions. These initiatives target both students and the general public. Notable examples include summer grants for undergraduate and graduate students to begin research, supervision of STEM research projects, and collaboration in the development of teaching materials and practical activities for vocational students.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_9_texto_buscado_1">scientific dissemination efforts</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_9_texto_buscado_2">STEM research projects</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 11-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_10_paragraph_0">iMATUS also takes part in programs such as “Collaborate and Innovate in Your Neighborhood”, promoted by the Santiago City Council, and organizes open-house events, conferences, and gatherings featuring Nobel Prizes and other prominent figures from the scientific community.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_10_texto_buscado_0">“Collaborate and Innovate in Your Neighborhood”</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 12-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_11_paragraph_0">On a global scale, the impact of iMATUS is demonstrated by more than one hundred registered patents and the creation of ten companies that originated directly from the center. In addition, iMATUS is part of international alliances and networks that promote collaboration between the public and private sectors, and it offers specialized services such as process and product quality control, concept testing, and technology audits for companies and research institutions.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_11_texto_buscado_0">more than one hundred registered patents</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 13-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_12_title_0">TALENT AMBASSADORS</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 14-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_title_0">MANAGEMENT TEAM</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_0">Director: Carmen Álvarez Lorenzo</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_1">Secretaria: Josefa Salgado Carballo</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_title_1">RESEARCH STAFF</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_2" translatable="false">Carmen Alvarez Lorenzo</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_3" translatable="false">Josefa Salgado Carballo</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_4" translatable="false">Alvaro Goyanes Goyanes</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_5" translatable="false">Francisco Javier Otero Espinar</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_6" translatable="false">Bárbara Blanco Fernández</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_7" translatable="false">Pablo Taboada Antelo</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_8" translatable="false">Carlos A. García-González</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_9" translatable="false">Patricia Díaz Rodríguez</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_10" translatable="false">Justo Arines Piferrer</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_11" translatable="false">Jorge Mira Pérez</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_12" translatable="false">Ana Rodríguez Bernaldo de Quirós</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_13" translatable="false">Jesús Liñares Beiras</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_14" translatable="false">Ana Isabel Gómez Varela</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_15" translatable="false">Xesús Prieto Blanco</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_16" translatable="false">María Elena López Lago</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_17" translatable="false">Maite Flores Arias</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_18" translatable="false">Mª del Carmen Bao Varela</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_19" translatable="false">María Jesús García Guimarey</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_20" translatable="false">Antonio Moreda Piñeiro</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_21" translatable="false">Carlos Vázquez Vázquez</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_13_paragraph_22" translatable="false">Luis Miguel Varela</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 15-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_14_title_0" translatable="false">CARMEN ÁLVAREZ LORENZO</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_14_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">CARMEN ÁLVAREZ LORENZO</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_14_title_1">Director</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_14_texto_buscado_1">Director</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_14_paragraph_0">Carmen Álvarez Lorenzo is Professor of Pharmacy and Pharmaceutical Technology and director of the Institute of Materials (iMATUS) at the USC. She is a full member of the Galician Royal Academy of Pharmacy and the Galician Royal Academy of Sciences, and a Fellow of the American Institute for Medical and Biological Engineering (AIMBE). She has 25 years of postdoctoral research in academic institutions in Spain and the USA (including MIT) and collaboration with hospitals and industry. His work lies at the intersection of materials science, biology, medicine and pharmaceutical technology. She has developed macro-, micro- and nano-scale drug delivery systems, drug-device combination products and scaffolds for regenerative medicine. She has published more than 400 articles in indexed journals and filed 20 patents. She is among the top 2% of the most cited researchers globally, collaborates with scientists from 33 countries and participates in several international project evaluation panels. She has mentored more than 100 pre- and postdoctoral researchers.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_14_paragraph_1">Her current research is focused on improving quality of life through personalised medicines and regenerative implants. She has designed medicated contact lenses with bio-inspired artificial receptors capable of releasing drugs in a controlled manner on the ocular surface. This breakthrough allows for prolonged and effective drug release, improving penetration into ocular tissues. These innovative lenses have positioned her team as pioneers in therapeutic hydrogels for ocular use and are being evaluated for clinical implementation with companies in the sector.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_14_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/58224/detalle?lang=es</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 16-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_15_title_0" translatable="false">JOSEFA SALGADO CARBALLO</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_15_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">JOSEFA SALGADO CARBALLO</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_15_title_1">Degree and PhD in Physics</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_15_texto_buscado_1">Degree and PhD in Physics</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_15_paragraph_0">Josefa Salgado, Professor of Applied Physics at the USC, has held the position of secretary of the Institute of Materials (iMATUS) since April 2023 and directed her department between 2014 and 2023. She has co-written more than 110 scientific and dissemination articles, and participated in more than 40 projects, networks and agreements with companies and public entities. Her career includes collaboration with a large number of European and American researchers and with 18 Spanish institutions, including universities, technology centres and companies. Her career highlights include the application of calorimetric techniques to analyse post-fire forest soils - a well-established methodology in soil science - and, recently, his collaboration with the Biological Mission of Galicia (CSIC) to develop flame-retardant foaming materials with low environmental impact. Together with Professor Luis M. Varela, she founded the Permanent Seminar on Energy Transition and Industrial Competitiveness (SPERTUS), which meets periodically to address issues such as energy capture, storage and efficiency.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_15_paragraph_1">Among her current lines, she leads the development of electrochemical storage systems based on semi-solid electrolytes with mixtures of ionic liquids and salts (lithium and multivalent), in silica and cellulose matrices, and silicon anodes and biocarbons from marine waste. This approach pursues the circular economy through the use of sustainable materials and the valorisation of waste, to promote efficient and environmentally friendly energy storage devices.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_15_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/60280/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 17-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_16_title_0" translatable="false">ÁLVARO GOYANES GOYANES</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_16_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">ÁLVARO GOYANES GOYANES</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_16_title_1">Pharmacist and Doctor of Pharmacy</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_16_texto_buscado_1">Pharmacist and Doctor of Pharmacy</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_16_paragraph_0">Alvaro Goyanes is an international leader in 3D printing of personalised medicines and emerging technologies in Pharmacy. Senior Lecturer at the Faculty of Pharmacy of the University of Santiago de Compostela and honorary professor at the UCL School of Pharmacy in London, his work drives personalised medicine. As co-founder and director of FABRX, the first company dedicated to printing customised medicines, he has developed GMP printers and software for manufacturing individual doses, including pharmaceutical inks and integrated quality control systems. Additionally, through the company FABRX Artificial Intelligence, he integrates AI to predict optimal doses and precise sensors, increasing the safety and efficacy of treatments. His scientific production exceeds one hundred articles, with more than 200 communications, and since 2019 he is among the ‘Highly Cited Researchers’ of Clarivate/Web of Science. With a PhD in Pharmacy from the USC and experience in community pharmacy, he brings a unique vision focused on the real needs of patients, committed to technologies that improve accessibility and therapeutic personalisation.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_16_paragraph_1">Our technology harnesses 3D printing to produce medicines tailored to each patient: with precise doses, combinations in a single dose, flavours or personalised forms that facilitate their administration. This innovation, applied in hospitals and pharmacies, improves the efficacy and safety of treatments and improves adherence, especially in children, the elderly and patients with rare diseases. In addition, it makes it possible to manufacture medicines ‘on-demand’ close to the patient, reducing errors, speeding up treatments and maximising safety and efficacy.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_16_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/280164/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 18-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_17_title_0" translatable="false">FRANCISCO JAVIER OTERO ESPINAR</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_17_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">FRANCISCO JAVIER OTERO ESPINAR</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_17_title_1">Doctor in Pharmacy. Specialist in Industrial and Galenic Pharmacy, and in Analysis and Control of Medicines and Drugs.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_17_texto_buscado_1">Doctor in Pharmacy. Specialist in Industrial and Galenic Pharmacy, and in Analysis and Control of Medicines and Drugs.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_17_paragraph_0">Francisco Javier Otero Espinar, Professor at the USC and coordinator of the interdisciplinary group PARAQUASIL, has extensive experience in the development of drugs for oral and parenteral administration, as well as innovative topical drug delivery systems in ophthalmology, skin and nails. He was dean of the Faculty of Pharmacy, director of the Department of Pharmacology, Pharmacy and Pharmaceutical Technology and president of the Spanish Society of Industrial and Galenic Pharmacy (SEFIG). Since May 2024 he has been editor-in-chief of the section ‘Drug Delivery and Controlled Release’ in the scientific journal Pharmaceutics, and associate editor in the Journal of Drug Delivery Science and Technology, both ranked in the top 25% in their field. Through his work, he pushes the scientific frontier, ensures the social quality of his research and is actively involved in the training of new professionals.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_17_paragraph_1">He leads research in the development of innovative pharmaceutical formulations for oral, parenteral and topical administration, especially in ophthalmic, dermal and nail applications. His work aims to improve the efficacy and safety of treatments for diseases such as age-related macular degeneration, diabetic retinopathy, lysosomal deposition pathologies, onychomycosis and nail psoriasis. It maintains close collaboration with the pharmaceutical industry and hospitals, which has facilitated the clinical application of some of its developments and the commercialisation of several of its patents. Its commitment to technology transfer is evidence of the social and clinical impact of its trajectory, contributing to the advancement of personalised treatment and the improvement of public health.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_17_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/59801/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 19-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_18_title_0" translatable="false">BÁRBARA BLANCO FERNÁNDEZ</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_18_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">BÁRBARA BLANCO FERNÁNDEZ</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_18_title_1">Pharmacist and PhD in Drug Research and Development</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_18_texto_buscado_1">Pharmacist and PhD in Drug Research and Development</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_18_paragraph_0">Bárbara Blanco Fernández is a Ramón y Cajal researcher at the University of Santiago de Compostela, with a solid international background at centres such as Michigan State University, Nottingham University and IBEC, as well as experience in industry. Her research focuses on advanced systems for the delivery of drugs and contrast agents in cancer treatment, and on the creation of tumour models using 3D bioprinting. She is currently leading innovative projects such as the bioprinting of tumours-on-a-chip 4D for drug screening and the development of 3D models that reproduce the tumour microenvironment and the immune system. Her contribution is key in the fight against cancer, combining scientific excellence and social impact.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_18_paragraph_1">She develops three-dimensional models of cancer using 3D bioprinting, reproducing ‘mini-tumours’ in the laboratory that mimic the complexity of human tumours. These models allow new therapies to be evaluated more quickly, accurately and realistically, improving the identification of effective treatments and favouring their clinical application. They also contribute to reducing the use of animals in experimentation, promoting a more ethical and sustainable science. One of the most relevant applications is personalised medicine: mini-tumours can be printed with cells from each patient to test different treatments on their specific tumour, facilitating the choice of the most effective therapy in each case. Her work is driving key advances in cancer research and in adapting treatments to the individual reality of each patient.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_18_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/1009154/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 20-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_19_title_0" translatable="false">PABLO TABOADA ANTELO</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_19_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">PABLO TABOADA ANTELO</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_19_title_1">Physicist and PhD in Materials Science</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_19_texto_buscado_1">Physicist and PhD in Materials Science</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_19_paragraph_0">Pablo Taboada Antelo is Professor of Condensed Matter Physics at the University of Santiago de Compostela (USC), where he leads the Colloid and Polymer Physics Group. His research focuses on the development of nanostructured materials for biomedical and energy applications, with particular emphasis on teragnosis, controlled drug release and regenerative medicine. He has supervised more than 20 doctoral theses and is the author of more than 260 scientific articles. His training includes stays at the universities of Bilbao, Manchester and University College Dublin. In addition, he has directed or participated in more than 50 national and international research projects. He is a regular reviewer for international journals and a member of the editorial board of Frontiers in Bioengineering, Pharmaceutics and Current Pharmaceutical Biotechnology. His scientific career has allowed him to gain a unique perspective on current challenges in the fields of diagnosis and treatment of diseases, as well as in energy storage, consolidating him as a reference in materials science and technology.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_19_paragraph_1">In the biomedical field, we design materials capable of acting as diagnostic and treatment agents, allowing the controlled and localised release of bioactive molecules by means of specific stimuli such as light, electric fields or ultrasound. This facilitates the selective destruction of diseased cells or tissues without affecting healthy ones, improving the precision and safety of treatments. In the field of energy, we are working on the creation of ion batteries with a storage capacity up to ten times greater than current ones, using optimised materials that allow for more compact systems that are easier to integrate into devices. These innovations aim to advance towards more personalised and sustainable therapies, as well as more efficient and accessible energy solutions, respectively.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_19_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/60452/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 21-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_20_title_0" translatable="false">CARLOS A. GARCÍA-GONZÁLEZ</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_20_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">CARLOS A. GARCÍA-GONZÁLEZ</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_20_title_1">PhD in Process Engineering and postgraduate degree in Innovation Management</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_20_texto_buscado_1">PhD in Process Engineering and postgraduate degree in Innovation Management</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_20_paragraph_0">Carlos A. García-González is Senior Lecturer of Pharmacy and Pharmaceutical Technology at the University of Santiago de Compostela (USC), with more than 20 years of international experience in countries such as Germany, Belgium, Portugal, France and the United Kingdom. Specialist in supercritical technology and industrialisation of products for the health, food and construction sectors, she coordinates the AerogelsLab, a world reference in aerogels. He participated in projects ranging from basic research to industrial optimisation, leading the development of a commercial thermal insulator and trials at Solvay plants, where he also applied Lean practices. At the USC, he promoted patents such as a synthetic bone implant in collaboration with a biosanitary multinational, a sterilisation method with the support of the State Research Agency and companies, and a sterilisation process integrated in the manufacture of aerogels, awarded in Europe and by the RAGC. It also coordinated a European COST network, consolidating its scientific and technological leadership.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_20_paragraph_1">Aerogels are nanostructured materials recognised as the lightest in the world, with unique properties of great industrial interest. In 2022, IUPAC included them in the Top-10 emerging technologies in chemistry. Unlike sponges or foams, they have high nanometric porosity and can be manufactured from a variety of polymeric sources. AerogelsLab specialises in engineering aerogels for the biomedical field, mainly using polysaccharides and proteins for their biocompatibility and low cost. Its research focuses on aerogels adapted for oral, pulmonary and cutaneous drug delivery, and regenerative medicine using 3D printing for implants with bioactive compounds. The lab is currently working on scaling up the technology for sustainable industrial production, looking to expand its clinical applications and beyond biomedicine.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_20_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/59072/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 22-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_21_title_0" translatable="false">PATRICIA DÍAZ RODRÍGUEZ</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_21_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">PATRICIA DÍAZ RODRÍGUEZ</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_21_title_1">PhD in Pharmacy</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_21_texto_buscado_1">PhD in Pharmacy</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_21_paragraph_0">Patricia Díaz Rodríguez is an expert researcher in the field of biomaterials for controlled release of therapeutic molecules and tissue regeneration. Throughout her career, she has demonstrated the usefulness of biomorphic ceramics as drug delivery systems, adapting to different mechanisms depending on the characteristics of the molecules and the material. She also studied how PDMS, polydopamine, calcium carbonate particles and the mechanical properties of substrates influence cellular response. She has also studied the communication between macrophages and chondrocytes in osteoarthritis, revealing the central role of inflammation in the progression of the disease and assessing the therapeutic potential of human mesenchymal stem cells. Her research contributes significantly to the advancement of biomaterials as innovative tools to treat chronic and inflammatory diseases, always with a clear focus on improving patients\' quality of life. In recognition of her career, she was appointed member of the board of directors of the Spain-Portugal section of the prestigious Controlled Release Society.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_21_paragraph_1">My research focuses on the development of new therapeutic strategies to enhance the body\'s ability to heal and regenerate itself. This includes tissue regeneration using advanced biomaterials, biological signals and bioengineering approaches to repair or replace damaged tissues or organs. I also employ gene therapy, seeking to correct DNA alterations or enhance cellular functions to improve healing processes. Finally, I study the modulation of the immune system, with the aim of balancing its response: activating it to fight diseases such as cancer or suppressing it in cases of autoimmunity. These lines of research open the door to more effective and personalised treatments with fewer side effects.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_21_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/120503/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 23-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_22_title_0" translatable="false">JUSTO ARINES PIFERRER</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_22_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">JUSTO ARINES PIFERRER</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_22_title_1">Degree and PhD in Physics, and diploma in Optics and Optometry.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_22_texto_buscado_1">Degree and PhD in Physics, and diploma in Optics and Optometry.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_22_paragraph_0">Justo Arines is the first University Professor in the area of Optometry at the University of Santiago de Compostela. Throughout his career he has received several awards, such as the Young Researcher Award in Optics (2003) and the Prize for the best thesis in Optical Imaging (2008), both awarded by SEDOPTICA, as well as the extraordinary PhD award (2006) and a business innovation award from the USC (2013). He worked at the University of Zaragoza (2005–2009) and, after a brief stay at the University of Vigo, he returned to the USC with a contract from the Parga Pondal programme (2010). He has held prominent positions in SEDOPTICA and currently coordinates the Spanish Committee of the International Day of Light, being a key figure in the dissemination of optics in Spain.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_22_paragraph_1">Throughout his career, Justo Arines developed a multidisciplinary profile focused on visual optics, being recognised nationally and internationally for his contributions in the measurement and correction of optical aberrations and refractive errors. He also worked on air disinfection with ultraviolet C light during the pandemic, collaborating in the development of an intelligent system tested at the CHUAC. He participated in the design of a luminaire to curb biological growth in built heritage and collaborated in light pollution measurements for the Porto Chamber of Commerce. In the LaserPET project, he helped to provide USC with a terawatt laser, working on the adaptive optics system. His applied research generated 8 patents, including self-adhesive glasses for presbyopia and amblyopia.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_22_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/58282/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 24-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_23_title_0" translatable="false">JORGE MIRA PÉREZ</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_23_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">JORGE MIRA PÉREZ</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_23_title_1">Degree and PhD in Physics</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_23_texto_buscado_1">Degree and PhD in Physics</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_23_paragraph_0">Jorge Mira Pérez has developed his career in various fields such as materials science (published with the Nobel Prize winner John B. Goodenough), medical physics, geography, mathematical modelling of social systems and civil, chemical and electrical engineering. He has received numerous awards for his academic and scientific career, including the Galicia Research Medal 2022 in the area of physics, mathematics and computer science. He is co-founder of the spin-off Ventilatio Lab, corresponding member of the Galician Royal Academy and president of the Deontological Commission of the Official College of Physicists of Spain. He was a member of the committee of experts of the Galician Government\'s Covid-19 and of the state commission for the reform of the official time. He was also an advisor to the Ministry of Education and Science for the creation of the Iberian International Nanotechnology Laboratory (INL).</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_23_paragraph_1">One of the most promising cancer therapies is CAR T, in which T lymphocytes are programmed to recognise specific tumour cells. It gives very promising results, but has some problems of efficacy in solid tumours. In the CARTsol project, coordinated by iMATUS, the programmed cells are packaged in nanocapsules in order to deliver them more efficiently to areas affected by solid tumours.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_23_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/59671/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 25-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_24_title_0" translatable="false">ANA RODRÍGUEZ BERNALDO DE QUIRÓS</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_24_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">ANA RODRÍGUEZ BERNALDO DE QUIRÓS</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_24_title_1">Degree and PhD in Pharmacy</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_24_texto_buscado_1">Degree and PhD in Pharmacy</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_24_paragraph_0">Ana Rodríguez Bernaldo de Quirós is Professor of Nutrition and Bromatology at the University of Santiago de Compostela, where she also obtained her degree and PhD in Pharmacy. She completed postdoctoral stays at Cornell University (USA), the Ricardo Jorge Institute (Portugal) and the Joint Research Center (Italy). She does research in the FoodChemPack group on chemical safety of food contact materials, developing analytical methods to identify intentionally added and unintentionally added substances, migration testing and evaluation of active packaging. She has participated in numerous projects and contracts with companies, supervised six PhD theses and published more than 100 scientific papers. Since July 2023, she represents Spain in the EFSA Scientific Network on Food Contact Materials.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_24_paragraph_1">The research line on chemical safety of food contact materials aims to ensure that these materials, such as packaging, do not pose health risks. Potentially migrant compounds are identified, tests are performed to measure their transfer to food and exposure in different population groups is estimated. In parallel, the line on active packaging develops materials incorporating antimicrobial or antioxidant compounds, some derived from food by-products, designed for controlled release into food. This makes it possible to maintain their quality, prolong their shelf life and contribute to sustainability through the recovery of agri-food waste.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_24_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/60124/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 26-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_25_title_0" translatable="false">JESÚS LIÑARES BEIRAS</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_25_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">JESÚS LIÑARES BEIRAS</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_25_title_1">Graduate and PhD in Physical Sciences</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_25_texto_buscado_1">Graduate and PhD in Physical Sciences</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_25_paragraph_0">Jesús Liñares Beiras is Professor of Optics at the USC, with more than 135 international publications (35% in quantum optics and 70% in integrated photonics). He supervised 10 PhD theses (2 more in progress), supervised more than 20 undergraduate and master\'s degree projects, and participated in 30 research projects (PI in 17). He was coordinator of the GOIFOMO (1994–2018) and QMatterPhotonics (2018–2022) groups, as well as of the interuniversity PhD programme in Laser, Photonics and Vision. He has stayed at international reference centres such as IFAC-CNR (Italy) and the University of Groningen (The Netherlands) , and has collaborated scientifically with researchers at NEC Labs America (USA) , CREOL (Florida) , the University of Bristol (UK) and the University of St. Petersburg (Russia) , among others. Together with Prof. G.C. Righini, he edited a book on ion exchange in glass. His achievements include participation in the world record for optical transmission over fibre (1.05 Pb/s in 2012).</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_25_paragraph_1">His research focuses on the theoretical and experimental development of Photonic Integrated Circuits (PICs) and Discrete Photonic Devices in glass, using ion exchange and material deposition techniques. These devices have applications in sensors, metrology and classical and quantum optical communications, especially in quantum cryptography (QKD), in order to guarantee secure communications against the future risks of quantum computing. He is currently leading projects to design passive, compact CFIs, compatible with existing fibre optic networks, that generate and measure true quantum light states without requiring complex optoelectronic support. In addition, he is scientific leader of several relevant projects: Quantum Communications-NextGenerationEU (subproject) , underwater QKD with the company NEC, collaboration with CESGA in QKD, PERTE-Chip-Televés project (subproject) , and development of integrated SPDC quantum sources (MICIU).</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_25_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/59412/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 27-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_26_title_0" translatable="false">ANA ISABEL GÓMEZ VARELA</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_26_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">ANA ISABEL GÓMEZ VARELA</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_26_title_1">Degree in Physics and PhD in photonics and laser technologies.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_26_texto_buscado_1">Degree in Physics and PhD in photonics and laser technologies.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_26_paragraph_0">My PhD focused on the development of optical materials for laser beam shaping, generating a patent and several publications. During my postdoctoral stage at the International Iberian Nanotechnology Laboratory, I participated in pioneering experiments in combined microscopy and initiated a line on non-invasive characterisation of lipid-genetic nanoparticles, with potential for the development of advanced vaccines. Since 2020, I have been researching personalised biomedical devices with laser technologies and 3D printing, a line supported by grants such as the Xunta de Galicia Postdoctoral Fellowship and the Ramón y Cajal contract. I also collaborate with the Transfer Area of the USC and develop outreach activities, such as online educational resources and programmes to promote scientific vocations, including ‘Meet the female researchers’ and ‘An engineer or scientist in every school’.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_26_paragraph_1">My research focuses on the development of biomedical and optical devices using advanced laser processing technologies, in particular two-photon polymerisation (2PP), which allows the creation of three-dimensional structures at the microscale. This technique will be applied to the functionalisation of contact lenses, allowing the addition of new functionalities such as controlled drug release or improved optical properties. In addition, I am working on the fabrication of specialised optical components, such as microlens arrays and phase sheets, with applications in presbyopia and advanced medical imaging.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_26_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/59191/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 28-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_27_title_0" translatable="false">XESÚS PRIETO BLANCO</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_27_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">XESÚS PRIETO BLANCO</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_27_title_1">Degree and PhD in Physics</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_27_texto_buscado_1">Degree and PhD in Physics</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_27_paragraph_0">Xesús Prieto Blanco is Senior Lecturer in the Department of Optics at the USC. He is co-author of more than 40 research articles published in indexed journals. He has participated in 6 contracts with companies and in 17 projects or contracts with public administrations, acting as Principal Investigator in 2 of them. He is a reviewer for the journals Applied Optics, Optics Communications and Journal of Lightwave Technology, and was guest editor of a special issue of the journal Applied Sciences. He actively collaborates with researchers at NEC Labs America and CREOL. One of the collaborative work has been recognised as one of the top 20 innovations of the year by Laser Focus World magazine (vol. 48, issue 12) , and another set world records for transmission capacity over a single optical fibre in 2012. He supervised 2 PhD theses and tutored numerous bachelor\'s and master\'s theses. In the teaching field, he taught more than 20 subjects in the Physics and Optics and Optometry degrees, as well as in three master\'s programmes.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_27_paragraph_1">His research aims to develop photonic chips that emit photons in pairs. This, along with other quantum properties of this light, has applications in quantum cryptography or quantum computing. The main novelty of the project is that the chips will be made of glass, which is much cheaper than the crystalline materials used so far. To achieve this, the glass must undergo a specific treatment, which also allows for new chip design strategies.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_27_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/59994/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 29-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_28_title_0" translatable="false">MARÍA ELENA LÓPEZ LAGO</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_28_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">MARÍA ELENA LÓPEZ LAGO</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_28_title_1">Degree in Physics, Degree in Physics, PhD in Physics with European PhD accreditation</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_28_texto_buscado_1">Degree in Physics, Degree in Physics, PhD in Physics with European PhD accreditation</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_28_paragraph_0">Throughout my research career, I have contributed to several fields of optics with versatility and impact. I started in integrated optics and, thanks to a Marie Curie grant, I researched nonlinear optics at IRCOM (Limoges), developing soliton generation techniques and characterisation of nolinearities. I also worked on ultrafast optics, wavefront sensors, hyperspectral imaging and optical studies of liquids and ionic gels, developing the RISBI technique. Recently, I have initiated lines on spinels and perovskites for biomedical applications. I supervised 5 doctoral theses and participated in 13 research projects, with more than 70 articles, 4 book chapters and 73 communications. I collaborate with national and international groups. My work ranges from characterisation of linear and nonlinear optical properties to development of optical instrumentation.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_28_paragraph_1">I am currently researching into multifunctional materials that contribute to increasing the efficiency of electrical and optical devices, such as photovoltaic solar panels or light-emitting diodes. We are looking for spinel-like materials with the aim of optimising the physical properties of interest.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_28_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/59464/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 30-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_29_title_0" translatable="false">MAITE FLORES ARIAS</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_29_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">MAITE FLORES ARIAS</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_29_title_1">PhD in Physics</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_29_texto_buscado_1">PhD in Physics</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_29_paragraph_0">Maite Flores is a leading researcher in the field of Optics and Photonics, with almost 30 years of experience. She coordinates the second most powerful laser facility in Spain and her work has contributed to advances in optical communications, imaging techniques and biomedical applications. She trained a dozen doctors who today work in leading international centres. Committed to scientific dissemination and equality, she participated in numerous projects to make women\'s scientific careers more visible. She has held relevant positions such as Secretary of the Executive Committee of the European Optical Society, is a Distinguished Researcher of the American Optical Society (OPTICA), and is currently a member of the Steering Committee of the European Optical Society and Vice-President of the Spanish Optical Society. She has just been appointed Fellow of the European Optical Society, EOS.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_29_paragraph_1">Her research focuses on the manufacture with laser technologies of microfluidic devices known as organs on a chip (OOC), which allow drugs to be studied in conditions similar to the human body, reducing the use of animal experimentation. This line contributes to the development of personalised medicine, improving the efficacy of treatments and reducing side effects, with the ultimate aim of favouring a better quality of life and healthier ageing.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_29_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/58977/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 31-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_30_title_0" translatable="false">Mª DEL CARMEN BAO VARELA</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_30_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">Mª DEL CARMEN BAO VARELA</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_30_title_1">PhD in Physical Science</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_30_texto_buscado_1">PhD in Physical Science</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_30_paragraph_0">Mª del Carmen Bao Varela is a member of the Photonics4Life group and principal investigator (PI) of the Microflex project. Currently, she directs the Department of Applied Physics at the University of Santiago de Compostela (USC). Her main lines of research focus on Gradient Gradient Index Media (GRIN) and on the various technologies and applications of lasers, both at industrial and biomedical level. In recent years, she has collaborated with different research groups and companies in studies on the disinfection of wastewater by irradiation with UV lasers, aimed at the degradation of drugs and other emerging pollutants. She has also worked on air purification, especially during the COVID-19 pandemic and its aftermath. She is involved in the European rePowerSiC project, which aims to develop a high-power laser emission system based on silicon carbide (SiC) to enable wireless power transfer over long distances in space.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_30_paragraph_1">The Microflex project aims to replicate blood vessels with high precision to study the formation of aneurysms and stenosis, and to explore treatments using nanoparticles. They are also looking at how the shape of the vessel influences blood flow and how this can be modified to guide drug-encapsulated nanoparticles to specific areas. Her research also covers optical interconnections and laser fabrication of materials, such as coatings to improve tactile accessibility in signage for the visually impaired.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_30_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/58311/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 32-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_31_title_0" translatable="false">MARÍA JESÚS GARCÍA GUIMAREY</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_31_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">MARÍA JESÚS GARCÍA GUIMAREY</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_31_title_1">PhD in Materials Science</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_31_texto_buscado_1">PhD in Materials Science</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_31_paragraph_0">María Jesús García Guimarey, Ramón y Cajal researcher at the University of Santiago de Compostela (USC), has participated in several research projects, both national and international, focused on the design of multifunctional lubricants and coatings. He has developed scientific collaborations with universities in the UK, Portugal and Spain, and is currently leading a project on environmentally friendly nanolubricants with anti-friction and anti-wear properties. His line of work stands out for its interdisciplinary approach, connecting materials science, mechanical engineering and sustainability.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_31_paragraph_1">Her research focuses on the study of low environmental impact nanomaterials that improve the performance of lubricants used in sustainable transport systems. These ecological lubricants, reinforced with nanoparticles, reduce friction between moving parts, prolonging the useful life of equipment and reducing energy consumption. This line of work has a strong impact on the development of cleaner and more sustainable technologies, contributing to the transition towards a greener economy.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_31_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/59074/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 33-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_32_title_0" translatable="false">ANTONIO MOREDA PIÑEIRO</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_32_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">ANTONIO MOREDA PIÑEIRO</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_32_title_1">Chemist and Doctor in Chemistry</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_32_texto_buscado_1">Chemist and Doctor in Chemistry</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_32_paragraph_0">Antonio Moreda Piñeiro is Professor of Analytical Chemistry at the University of Santiago de Compostela and a pioneer in the synthesis of quantum dots (Q.) based on non-toxic materials such as Mn-ZnS and carbon dots. He combines these nanomaterials with molecularly imprinted polymers (MIP) to create highly selective detection phases, useful in the development of environmental and clinical sensors. It is also a leader in Spain in nanometrology and nanotoxicology, developing analytical platforms to detect nanomaterials in food, environments and clinical samples, and assessing their toxicity. It is part of the Nanoscience and Analytical Nanotechnology Thematic Network and the NyNA Consortium, leaders in nanometrology in Spain.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_32_paragraph_1">The development of sensors based on quantum dots combined with molecularly imprinted polymers (QDs-MIP) enables the rapid and cost-effective detection of contaminants in complex samples such as blood, urine and saliva, useful for detecting drugs of abuse, aflatoxins in food and heavy metals in fish and seafood. The nanometrology line has established baseline levels of inorganic nanoparticles in the Galician environment, especially in purified water and fish products, a key sector in the region. In addition, nanotoxicity studies have revealed the high biopersistence of titanium dioxide nanoparticles in the digestive tract, supporting the prohibition of the additive E171 by the European Food Safety Agency, highlighting the relevance of these studies for public health.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_32_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/59699/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 34-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_33_title_0" translatable="false">CARLOS VÁZQUEZ VÁZQUEZ</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_33_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">CARLOS VÁZQUEZ VÁZQUEZ</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_33_title_1">PhD in Chemical Sciences</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_33_texto_buscado_1">PhD in Chemical Sciences</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_33_paragraph_0">Carlos Vázquez Vázquez is Senior Lecturer of Physical Chemistry at the USC and researcher at the Institute of Materials. He has extensive experience in the synthesis and chemical characterisation of nanomaterials, after postdoctoral stays in France, Japan and Germany. He is a founding partner and scientific advisor of the company NANOGAP, dedicated to the commercialisation of nanomaterials. He has more than 100 publications and has participated in 33 competitive projects, including European, national and regional projects, as well as 6 contracts with companies. He is co-inventor of 5 patents, some of them extended to Europe and the United States. His interests cover the synthesis and properties of nanomaterials, nanostructured systems, colloidal self-organisation, metallic nanoclusters and directional growth of nanomaterials such as cylinders and fibres.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_33_paragraph_1">His main line of research focuses on the preparation of nanomaterials for heterogeneous catalysis in liquid or gas phase, with or without light. These catalysts combine semiconducting oxides and metal nanoclusters, materials with molecular properties different from traditional metals. He has worked on projects to remove emerging pollutants in wastewater (antibiotics, analgesics, oestrogens), in collaboration with the CRETUS institute of the USC, using catalytic and photocatalytic magnetic nanomaterials, facilitating their recovery. Recently, he has developed nanomaterials for gas-phase catalysis, with applications in the photoproduction of hydrogen for energy and in artificial photosynthesis to remove carbon dioxide, transforming it into industrial compounds such as synthesis gas, alcohols and light hydrocarbons such as methanol or methane.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_33_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/60592/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 35-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_34_title_0" translatable="false">LUIS MIGUEL VARELA</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_34_texto_buscado_0" translatable="false">LUIS MIGUEL VARELA</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_34_title_1">Degree and PhD in Physics and Degree in Law</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_34_texto_buscado_1">Degree and PhD in Physics and Degree in Law</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_34_paragraph_0">Luis Miguel Varela, Professor of Particle Physics (Condensed Matter) at the USC, is a specialist in thermodynamics, statistical mechanics, statistical analysis, econophysics and renewable energies. He was Dean of the Faculty of Physics (2010–2018) and coordinated the Masters in Physics and Renewable Energies, as well as the PhD in Renewable Energies and Energy Sustainability. He coordinates the Nanomaterials, Photonics and Soft Matter Group and chairs the European Ion Matter Society, with more than 60 researchers. He is a member of European platforms on batteries and advises the Xunta de Galicia on energy storage and hydrogen. He founded the Permanent Seminar on Energy Transition and Industrial Competitiveness (SPERTUS), which brings together multidisciplinary experts. He was technical director of the Galician Hydrogen Association and vice-president of the Silkway network for Europe-Asia cooperation in energy and sustainability. He has published more than 160 papers and supervised 14 doctoral theses.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_34_paragraph_1">His research focuses on the statistical mechanics of complex systems, especially ionic liquids and charged fluids, and on complex networks applied to epidemics and socio-economic systems. He works on advanced electrolytes for electrochemical storage (batteries, supercapacitors) and photonic devices, as well as on thermal energy storage. He coordinates regional, national and European projects, collaborates with international universities and is inventor of several patents on energy devices and materials.</string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_34_paragraph_2">MORE INFO: https://investigacion.usc.gal/investigadores/60527/detalle</string>

    <!--PANTALLA 36-->
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_35_title_0" translatable="false"> https://imatus.usc.es/ </string>
    <string name="II_IMATUS_miniscreen_35_paragraph_0">If you are interested in learning more about iMATUS you can access more information by clicking on the following link</string>

</resources>