<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


    <!-- INCIFOR MiniScreen0 -->
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_0_paragraph_0">The DNA of all human beings is 99.6% identical, but the information contained in that unique 0.4% is essential for obtaining important answers. In Spain, nearly 9,000 bodies have been recovered from more than 700 mass graves that have been excavated. The work of identifying the remains, carried out through genetic genealogy, is essential to bring closure to the families of the missing.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_1_paragraph_0">Between 30 and 50% of fatal traffic accidents involve individuals who were driving under the influence of alcohol. In these cases, it is very important to determine whether a person\'s actions were influenced by the presence of drugs in their system.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_2_paragraph_0">Improvements in the processes and instruments used by forensic science have led to a huge qualitative leap in the resolution of legal issues. From genetic tests that determine kinship to DNA samples that prove the perpetrator of a crime. From the presence of toxins in violent crimes to the first step in addressing the situation of a drug addict. Forensic science has a direct and clear impact on people in such fundamental aspects of their lives as honour, justice and death.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_3_paragraph_0">With the aim of serving as a centre of reference in teaching and research, as well as advising the Administration of Justice, the ‘Luís Concheiro’ Institute of Forensic and Criminological Sciences (INCIFOR) has been created, whose areas of expertise are Legal Medicine, Toxicology and Criminology.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_4_paragraph_0">The “Luís Concheiro” Institute of Forensic and Criminological Sciences (INCIFOR) offers a wide portfolio of services that are available to both public and private organizations.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_5_paragraph_0">"The Luis Concheiro Institute of Forensic and Criminological Sciences (INCIFOR) (formerly the Institute of Legal Medicine), based in Santiago de Compostela, is a mixed institution of international renown in the fields of legal medicine, toxicology, and forensic genetics. "</string>

    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_6_title_0" translatable="false">1978</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_6_title_1" translatable="false">1992</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_6_title_2" translatable="false">2025</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_6_paragraph_0">It was created by Decree (Galician) 247/1992, of July 30, following an agreement between the University of Santiago de Compostela (USC) and the Regional Government of Galicia, although it has been conducting research and providing services since 1978. </string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_6_paragraph_1">Since 2025, it has had a Criminology Unit, the result of the integration of what was until then the USC Institute of Criminology, promoter and coordinator of the university\'s own degree in Criminology, now a Bachelor\'s Degree in Criminology.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_6_paragraph_2">Start of activity</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_6_paragraph_3">Official creation</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_6_paragraph_4">Integration of Criminology</string>

    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_7_paragraph_0">O Instituto, cuxa sede se sitúa no edificio histórico da Facultade de Medicina de Santiago de Compostela, participa activamente na formación de estudantes dos graos de Medicina, Dereito, Criminoloxía e Farmacia, entre outros, así como de estudantes de distintos másteres.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_7_paragraph_1">It is responsible for the USC Doctorate programme ‘Advances and New Strategies in Forensic Sciences’. It also collaborates with various national and international universities in the undergraduate and postgraduate training of their students.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_8_paragraph_0">INCIFOR also participates in training activities for Justice Administration personnel and serves as a reference centre for internships in its Toxicology and Forensic Genetics laboratories for criminology students and vocational training students.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_9_paragraph_0">INCIFOR carries out extensive expert work in the field of Forensic Genetics and Toxicology under the annual agreement between the USC and the Regional Government of Galicia. It works closely with the Courts of Justice and State security forces. It has signed agreements and contracts with various public and private administrations to carry out analyses and other expert activities.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_10_paragraph_0">"Its extensive research capacity has enabled it to develop and implement advanced methods of genetic analysis and toxicological analysis in its daily activities. "</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_10_paragraph_1">"INCIFOR's research track record has led to advances in knowledge and innovation in the field of forensic science, as well as in the resolution of legal cases based on the analysis of various samples and biological remains. "</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_10_paragraph_2">All these advances and research activities have positioned INCIFOR as an international centre of excellence in the field of forensic medicine and toxicology.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_11_paragraph_0">INCIFOR\'s work not only contributes to solving cases, but also drives scientific advances in forensic medicine, toxicology, forensic genetics and criminology. Its work has a direct impact on justice, security and the training of highly qualified professionals.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_11_paragraph_1">INCIFOR has 14 teaching and research staff members and 6 affiliated researchers.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_12_paragraph_0">The Institute of Forensic and Criminological Sciences of Santiago de Compostela is a leader in scientific research applied to solving legal cases and, ultimately, improving public safety.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_13_paragraph_0">INCIFOR is structured into five units:</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_13_paragraph_1">Forensic Genetics</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_13_paragraph_2">Forensic Toxicology</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_13_paragraph_3">Clinical and Behavioral Toxicology</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_13_paragraph_4">Pathology and Forensic Clinic</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_13_paragraph_5">Criminology</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_14_title_0">Forensic</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_14_title_1"> Genetics</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_14_paragraph_0">Here, DNA is analysed to identify individuals, establish kinship or solve crimes. They also work on identifying victims of disasters and studying ancient human remains.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_15_title_0">Forensic</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_15_title_1">Toxicology</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_15_paragraph_0">Its activity focuses on the analysis of biological samples from living or deceased persons for the detection, identification and quantification of drugs, alcohol, poisons and all types of substances in the context of judicial investigations, such as homicides, accidents or cases of chemical submission. \nMany types of biological samples are analysed in its laboratory, in many cases revealing recent consumption and, in others, prolonged exposure over time to different types of substances, making it possible to establish a retrospective chronology of their consumption. This laboratory is constantly developing and publishing new analytical methods in influential scientific journals that improve the ability to detect and quantify new substances.\n</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_16_title_0">"Clinical and Behavioural "</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_16_title_1">Toxicology</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_16_paragraph_0">The group is composed of a team of expert toxicologists specialising in the analytical determination of psychoactive substances whose effect on human behaviour can have serious consequences, both for the individual and for society. This unit carries out analyses requested by hospital emergency services in cases of poisoning. In addition, they have agreements with various local police forces for the control of drugs of abuse, confirming the saliva tests carried out by them.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_17_title_0">Pathology and Forensic</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_17_title_1">" Medicine"</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_17_paragraph_0">Its activity is focused on developing new methods and strategies in the field of Pathology and Forensic Medicine to resolve important issues in different areas of law: time of death, medical-legal cause and aetiology of death, personal identification, assessment of bodily harm, domestic violence.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_18_title_0">Criminology</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_18_paragraph_0">It carries out teaching work in the Criminology degree programme and specialised training for institutions and professionals in this field, as well as research and advisory work in this area.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_19_title_0">Forensic</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_19_title_1"> Genetics</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_19_paragraph_0">Through its areas of research—forensic genetics, forensic toxicology, clinical toxicology, forensic pathology, and criminology—INCIFOR has participated in numerous high-profile cases at the Galician, national, and international levels.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_19_paragraph_1">Identification and Justice</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_20_paragraph_0">The genetic analyses carried out in this laboratory have made it possible to solve high-profile murder cases in Spain, even years after they were committed.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_20_paragraph_1">Identification of disaster victims: They have collaborated in the identification of victims in tragedies such as the 11 March attacks in Madrid, applying advanced DNA techniques in extreme conditions.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_20_paragraph_2">Exhumation of Civil War graves: They participate in the recovery and identification of remains from the Civil War, restoring identity and dignity to families who had been waiting decades for answers.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_21_title_0">FORENSIC AND CLINICAL</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_21_title_1">TOXICOLOGY</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_21_paragraph_0">Detecting the invisible, protecting lives</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_21_paragraph_1">The main fields of application at present are:</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_21_paragraph_2">●	Analytical diagnosis of acute clinical poisoning</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_21_paragraph_3">●	Expert activity for the Administration of Justice</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_21_paragraph_4">●	Drug control in road traffic</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_21_paragraph_5">Other types of analysis carried out:</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_21_paragraph_6">●	Diagnosis of foetal exposure to drugs during pregnancy</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_21_paragraph_7">●	Drug control in the workplace</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_21_paragraph_8">●	Cases of chemical submission.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_21_paragraph_9">●	Analysis for individuals</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_22_title_0">Pathology</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_22_title_1"> and Forensic Medicine</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_22_paragraph_0">This Unit is responsible for providing forensic medical expertise, issuing reports and opinions on the assessment of bodily harm, date and cause of death, exhumations and expertise related to medical liability in criminal, civil and administrative matters.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_23_title_0">Criminology</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_23_paragraph_0">It offers advisory services (reports, opinions, studies, regulatory projects and regulatory compliance programmes) to professionals and public and private entities in the field of criminology and criminal sciences. It also offers specialised training on demand for all institutions and professionals involved or interested in these areas.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_24_paragraph_0">INCIFOR is a clear example of how science improves people\'s lives. Its work does not stay in the laboratories: it reaches the courts, hospitals and also families seeking answers. Thanks to the application of scientific knowledge, they have managed to solve crimes, clarify deaths, help victims, train new professionals and provide evidence that ensures justice is based on objective, clear and demonstrable facts.</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_25_title_0">TALENT </string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_25_title_1">AMBASSADORS</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_26_paragraph_0">Prueba Directivo 1</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_26_paragraph_1">Prueba Directivo 2</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_27_title_0">Prueba directivo1</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_27_title_1">Prueba directivo2</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_27_paragraph_1">Prueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivoPrueba texto directivo</string>
    <string name="More_info">More Info here</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_28_paragraph_0">Director</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_29_paragraph_0">Secretary</string>
    <string name="II_INCIFOR_miniscreen_50_paragraph_0">\tIf you are interested in learning more about INCIFOR you can access more information by clicking on the following link</string>

</resources>